Finding Aid for Dept. of History (University of Michigan) student papers, 1930-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dept. of History (University of Michigan) student papers
1930-1987
University of Michigan. Dept. of History.
8821 Bimu C26 2
Student papers, 1930-1987 prepared for classes in history at the University of Michigan (primarily Michigan history class taught by Lewis G. VanderVelde, but also including research papers for classes taught by Sidney Fine and others); topics concern Michigan social and political history; Michigan biography and bibliography; and local community history.
7 linear feet 263 papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were received from donor no. 1991.
The record group is open without restriction.
From the founding of the university until the Tappan administration, the study of history was part of the teaching of other disciplines. The appointment of Andrew Dickson White (1857) as professor of history and English literature marked the beginning of historical teaching of the modern type. History was included in the newly established School of Political Science in 1881; it eventually became a department in the College of Literature, Science and the Arts. Lewis G VanderVelde was both a professor of history and director of the Michigan Historical Collections; Sydney Fine is a professor of history and also involved in the direction of the Michigan Historical Collections through its board of directors.
The student papers are organized alphabetically by author in two series, which are similar in date range and topics covered. Topics of papers concern Michigan social and political history; Michigan biography and bibliography; local community history and University of Michigan history. A topical index to the papers is available in the first box of the collection.
Subjects:
Academic freedom.; Actresses.; Adams, Henry Carter, 1851-1921.; Adrian (Mich.); African Americans--Michigan.; Alger County (Mich.); American Fur Company.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.: Township); Ann Arbor argus.; Mayors--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Astor, John Jacob, 1763-1848.; Automobile industry and trade--United States.; Bagley, John Judson, 1832-1881.; Ball, John, 1794-1884.; Barry County (Mich.); Bingham, Kinsley S. (Kinsley Scott), 1808-1861.; Birmingham (Mich.); Birth control.; Black Legion.; Blair, Austin, 1818-1894.; Blois, John T.; Bonstelle, Laura Justine, 1872-1932.; Booker T. Washington Trade Association.; Brewer family.; British Americans--Michigan.; Canada.; Canada--History--Rebellion, 1837-1838.; Canals.; Carton, John J. (John Jay), 1856-1934.; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866.; Chandler, Elizabeth Margaret, 1807-1834.; Chapin, Roy D. (Roy Dikeman), 1880-1936.; Civil service.; Christiancy, Isaac Peckham, 1812-1890.; Michigan State Public School, Coldwater.; Communist college teachers.; Congregational churches.; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Cooley, Thomas McIntyre, 1824-1898.; Copeland, Royal S. (Royal Samuel), 1868-1938.; Coply, Alexander Bennett, 1822-1899.; Copper mines and mining--Michigan--Upper Peninsula.; Cornish--Michigan.; Crapo, Henry Howland, 1804-1869.; Crary, Isaac Edwin, 1804-1854.; Custer, George Armstrong, 1839-1876.; Dearborn (Mich.)--Schools.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Demography.; Depressions--1836-1837--United States.; Depressions--1929--Michigan.; Detroit (Mich.); Detroit gazette.; Detroit (Mich.). House of Correction.; Detroit Housewives League (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Schools--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit Young Men's Society.; Detroit University School.; Detroit Urban League.; Dickinson County (Mich.); Dougherty, Peter, 1805-1894.; Douglas, Lloyd C. (Lloyd Cassel), 1877-1951.; Drama.; Dutch Americans--Michigan.; Michigan State Normal College.; Education--Michigan.; Elections--Michigan--1885.; Elections--Michigan--1912.; Elections--Michigan--1918.; Elections--Michigan--1932.; Elections--Michigan--1944.; Elections--Michigan--1962.; Elections--Michigan.; Michigan--Emigration and immigration.; Family.; Farm life--Michigan.; Ferris, Woodbridge N., 1853-1928.; Ferry, William Montague, 1796-1867.; First Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); First Methodist Episcopal Church (Jackson, Mich.); First Presbyterian Church (Dearborn, Mich.); Fitch, Abel F. d. 1851.; Folklore.; Football--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.; Forests and forestry--Michigan.; Foster, Theodore, 1812-1865.; Frontier and pioneer life--Michigan.; Furniture industry and trade--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Gazetteer of the state of Michigan.; General Motors Corporation.; German Americans--Michigan.; Good Roads Movement.; Grand Rapids (Mich.); Grape industry.; Great Lakes Steel Corporation.; Greek letter societies--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Haviland, Laura S. (Laura Smith), 1808-1898.; Hall, Emma Amelia, 1837-1884.; Hannah and Lay Company.; Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1887-1945.; Helme, James W., 1860-1938.; Michigan Historical Records Survey.; Hazing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Historical Society of Michigan (1874- ); Holland (Mich.); Hull, William, 1753-1825.; Indians of North America--Michigan.; Industries--Michigan--Detroit.; Industrial Workers of the World.; Inkster (Mich.); American newspapers--Michigan--Inkster.; Insurance--Michigan.; International Congress of Women (1915: Hague, Netherlands); International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America.; Ionia (Mich.: Township); Iosco County (Mich.); Iosco County gazette.; Iron River (Mich.); Isle Royale (Mich.); Jackson (Mich.); Kalamazoo (Mich.); W. K. Kellogg Foundation.; Ke-taw-kah.; Keweenaw County (Mich.); Keweenaw Peninsula (Mich.); Kindergarten.; Labadie, Jo, 1850-1933.; Labadie Collection (Harlan Hatcher Graduate Library); Labor--Michigan.; Ladies Library Association of Ann Arbor.; Langlade, Charles Michel de, 1729-1800.; Legislation--Michigan.; Libel and slander.; Libraries--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.; Livonia (Mich.); Logging--Michigan.; Louis, Joe, 1914-1981.; Lumberman's Memorial (Iosco County, Mich.); Luce County (Mich.); Lyceums--Michigan.; Lyon, Lucius, 1800-1851.; Mackinac Island (Mich.); Manchester (Mich.: Township); Manwaring, Joshua, 1824-1903.; Marshall (Mich.); Marygrove College.; Medicine--Michigan.; Mendon (Mich.); Mennonites--Michigan.; Merrill, Howard E.; Mershon, Wm. B. (William Butts), 1856-1943.; Methodist Protestant Church (U.S.: 1830-1939)--Michigan.Michigan.; Methodist Episcopal Church--Michigan--Ann Arbor.MichiganAnn Arbor.; Methodist Episcopal Church--Michigan--Jackson.MichiganJackson.; Michigan--Bibliography.; Michigan. Board of State Canvassers.; Michigan--Boundaries--Ohio.; Michigan--Boundaries--Wisconsin.; Michigan College of Mining and Technology.; Michigan. Constitutional Convention (1850); Michigan. Constitutional Convention (1907-1908); Michigan daily.; Michigan. Insurance Bureau.; Michigan--History.; Michigan. Legislature. (17th: 1853); Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Michigan Pioneer and Historical Society.; Michigan--Politics and government--1815-1844.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1845-1860.; Michigan--Politics and government--1877-1898.; Michigan--Politics and government--1899-1916.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Michigan--Population.; Michigan School of Religion.; Michigan. Dept. of State.; Michigan State Police.; Michigan Steel Corporation.; Michigan. Supreme Court.; Migration, Internal.; Missions--Michigan.; Missionaries--Michigan.; Moore, Charles, 1855-1942.; Morgan, Angela, 1874-1957.; Municipal government--Michigan.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Music--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Muskegon (Mich.); National Steel Corporation.; Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.; Newburgh (Livonia, Mich.); Newett, George A., b. 1856.; American newspapers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Northville (Mich.); Schools--Michigan--Northville.; Norvell, John, 1789-1850.; Ojibwa Indians.; Old Mission (Mich.); Old Territorial Road (Mich.); Olivet College.; Parkhurst, John G. (John Gibson), 1824-1906.; Paw Paw (Mich.); Peace--Societies, etc.; Pennfield (Mich.: Township); Philippines--History--1898-1946.; Pingree, Hazen S., 1840-1901.; Pierce, John Davis, 1797-1882.; Police--Michigan.; Political Equality Club (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Presbyterian Church--Michigan.Michigan.; Presbyterian Church--Michigan--Dearborn.MichiganDearborn.; Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. Presbytery of Washtenaw (Mich.); Prisons--Michigan.; Progressivism (United States politics); Prohibition--Michigan.; Public lands--Michigan.; Public welfare--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Railroads--Michigan.; Randall, Caleb Dwinell, 1831-1903.; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877); Redford (Mich.: Township); Redford Baptist Church (Detroit, Mich.); Republican Party (Mich.); Resorts--Michigan--Mackinac Island.; Rich, John Treadway, 1841-1926.; Richard, Gabriel, 1767-1832.; Roads--Michigan.; Romney, George W., 1907-1995.; Plank roads--Michigan.; Round Table Club (University of Michigan); Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Royal Oak (Mich.: Township); Royal Oak daily tribune.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Saginaw River Valley (Mich.); St. James Episcopal Church (Birmingham, Mich.); Saint Joseph County (Mich.); Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.); Sault Sainte Marie Canal (Mich.); Schoolcraft County (Mich.); Schools--Michigan.; Scio (Mich.: Township); Seaman, Ezra C. (Ezra Champion), 1805-1880.; Shipping--Michigan--Sault Sainte Marie.; Smith, Arvilla Almira Powers, 1808-1895.; Antislavery movements--United States.; Society of Friends--Michigan.Michigan.; Soule, Harrison, 1832-1922.; Southfield High School (Mich.); Michigan State Prison.; Steel industry and trade--Michigan.; Stevens family.; Strang, James Jesse, 1813-1856.; Strikes and lockouts--Michigan.; Sweet, Ossian, 1895-1960.; Taxation--Michigan.; Theaters--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Transportation--Michigan.; Traverse City (Mich.); Michigan--Description and travel.; Northwest, Old--Description and travel.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 15th (1862-1865); United States--Foreign relations--Canada.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States--History--French and Indian War, 1755-1763.; United States. Interstate Commerce Commission.; Universities and colleges--Michigan.; University of Michigan. Board of Regents.; University of Michigan--Branches.Branches.; University of Michigan--Dramatics.Dramatics.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; University of Michigan--Football.Football.; University of Michigan--History.History.; University of Michigan--Religion.Religion.; University of Michigan--Sports.Sports.; University of Michigan--Students--Conduct of life.StudentsConduct of life.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1921-1930.StudentsSocial life and customs1921-1930.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1931-1940.StudentsSocial life and customs1931-1940.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1841-1850.StudentsSocial life and customs1841-1850.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1851-1860.StudentsSocial life and customs1851-1860.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1871-1880.StudentsSocial life and customs1871-1880.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.StudentsSocial life and customs1961-1970.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.StudentsSocieties, etc.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Van Osdel, Oliver Willis, 1846-1935.; Van Raalte, Albertus C. (Albertus Christiaan), 1811-1876.; Warner, Frederick Maltby, 1865-1923.; Washtenaw County (Mich.); Water power.; Wealthy Street Baptist Church (Grand Rapids, Mich.); Western Methodist Protestant.; Wheeler, Clara Marian, 1861-1946.; White Panther Party.; Wisconsin--Boundaries--Michigan.; Women--Suffrage--Michigan.; Women--Michigan--Societies and clubs.; Women's rights--Michigan.; Young Men's Christian Associations.; Ypsilanti (Mich.); Young Woman's Home Association of Detroit.; Spanish-American War, 1898.; Mexican War, 1846-1848.; World War, 1914-1918--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; World War, 1914-1918--Education and the war.; Women college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; World War, 1939-1945.; Netherlands--Emigration and immigration.; Redford (Detroit, Mich.); Ohio--Boundaries--Michigan.; Wisconsin--Boundaries--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Contributors:
Fine, Sidney, 1920-; Jones, J. Weldon (James Weldon), 1896-; Vander Velde, Lewis G. (Lewis George), 1890-1975.; Warner, Robert M. (Robert Mark), 1927-2007.
- Series I
  - Achenbaum, W. Andrew
    - Nineteenth Century Michigan Families Revisited, or, Sex and the Simple Girl", 1972 (Box 1)
      (History 799)
  - Agren, Elizabeth.
    - "A History of the Redford Baptist Church", 1958 (Box 1)
    - "Kinsley Scott Bingham and the Slave Controversy", 1958 (Box 1)
  - Aikman, J. Leo
    - "Isle Royale Bibliography" (Box 1)
  - Albaugh, James J.
    - "A Brief History of Michigan From the Close of the American Revolution Through the Civil War", 1953 (Box 1)
      (History 129s)
  - Alden, Bernice (Wright)
    - "The Quakers in Michigan: with especial reference to the period of the administration of President Andrew Jackson, 1829-1837" (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Ernest
    - "The Spring Election of 1885 in Michigan: with special reference to the Defeat of Judge Thomas M. Cooley for the Supreme Court", 1950 (Box 1)
      (History 336)
  - Allen, Francine
    - "The Golden Age of Peace", 1984 (Box 1)
      (History 196)
  - Bachman, Anne
    - "Religion and the University of Michigan, 1817-1837" (Box 1)
      (History, 393)
  - Ballou, Isabel A.
    - "The Struggle for the Development of Transportation into the Saginaw Valley, Prior to 1840" (Box 1)
      (History 259)
  - Batsakis, Angelo
    - "Charles Michel Mouet de Langlade: The Unsung Hero of the French and Indian War" (Box 1)
  - Beatty, Kenneth
    - "The Michigan Republican State Convention of 1912: A Study in Michigan Politics, January-April, 1912", 1960 (Box 1)
      (History 344)
  - Beebe, Grace C.
    - "Bibliography on Michilimackinac and Mackinac Island", 1942 (Box 1)
    - "John Jacob Astor and the American Fur Company at Mackinac Island, 1809-1834", 1942 (Box 1)
      (History 335-336)
  - Behringer, Clara M.
    - "A History of the Theatre in Ann Arbor, beginnings-1870", 1949 (Box 1)
  - Behringer, Clara M.
    - "The University and the Theatre: Ann Arbor and the Theatre: The Newspapers Report on an Interim, 1904-07" (Box 1)
  - Belknap, John
    - "Institutions and Individuals in a Michigan City, 1906-1914", 1963 (Box 1)
      (History 629)
  - Bidlack, Russell E.
    - "The Board of Regents of the University of Michigan, 1837-1852" 1949) (Box 1)
  - Blum, Harriet L.
    - "Congress and the Canadian Rebellion of 1837-1838", 1931 (Box 1)
  - Booth, Carol J.
    - "The Branches of the University", 1944 (Box 1)
      (E201)
  - Bowdish, Harold.
    - "Tales of Early Travels Through Michigan", (Michigan History 171s, 1941 (Box 1)
    - "A Brief Outline of United States History with Special Reference to the History of Michigan" (Box 1)
      (Michigan History 171s)
  - Boyer, Robert S.
    - "Plank Roads on Michigan 1844-1861", 1941 (Box 1)
  - Bradshaw, James A.
    - "The Furniture Industry in Grand Rapids to 1880" (Box 1)
  - Braidwood, Charles D.
    - "The Executive Removal of the Board of State Canvassers in 1894" (Box 1)
      (Michigan Seminar)
  - Buchner, William E.
    - "The Grand Rapids Furniture Strike of 1911", (, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Burrows, Edwin Gwynne
    - "The Making of an Author: Twenty Years in the Life of Lloyd C. Douglas", 1964 (Box 1)
    - "Canadian Reciprocity, 1911 Protecting the Empire", 1964 (Box 1)
  - Burtle, Frances
    - "History Stories of Early Grand Rapids", 1941 (Box 1)
      (History 171s)
    - "The Story of Transportation Through Michigan History", 1941 (Box 1)
  - Cargo, Ruth E.
    - "The Western Methodist Protestant", 1952 (Box 1)
  - Casmer, Nancy L.
    - "The History of the Development of Education in Dearborn School District Number Seven, Prior to 1926" (Box 1)
      (History 335)
    - "The History of the First Presbyterian Church of Dearbornville, 1831-1847" (Box 1)
  - Cavanagh, Eleanor I.
    - "The Department of Insurance of the State of Michigan Life Insurance Supervision, 1906-1911" (Box 1)
      (History 201s)
  - Cobb, Anita Smith
    - "The Negro in the Inkster Village Council", 1958 (Box 2)
      (Seminar 335)
  - Cook, Alice
    - "The Katokoh Trial", 1947 (Box 2)
  - Cooke, Geneva M.
    - "The School Newspaper of Michigan State Normal College Through the Years 1893-1905", 1955 (Box 2)
      (Social History 335)
  - Cousino, Paul Kenneth
    - "The History of the Michigan State Prison at Jackson, Michigan from 1838-1850", 1936 (Box 2)
  - Creaser, Moira
    - "The Iosco County Gazette: 1868-1878", 1944 (Box 2)
      (American History 335s)
  - Critchett, Mary
    - "Bibliography for Isaac E. Crary", 1935 (Box 2)
      (American History)
  - Dean, William L
    - "Miss Jessie Bonstelle, 1869-1890" (Box 2)
  - Dodge, Elise F.
    - "The Ohio-Michigan Boundary Dispute", 1932 (Box 2)
      (History 259-260)
  - Doolen, Richard M.
    - "The Partisan Press in Barry County Michigan: Chapter Two -- Mr. Smith and Mrs. Nevins (1857-1860)", 1959 (Box 2)
  - Doolittle, Doris
    - "National Measures Discussed by Our First United States Senators from Michigan" (Box 2)
  - Drachler, Norman
    - "Religion and the University of Michigan, 1837-1875" (Box 2)
  - Dusenberry, William
    - "The Michigan State Police Communication System", 1939 (Box 2)
      (History 260)
  - Dwelle, Margaret
    - "Charles Moore", 1943 (Box 2)
      (History 341s)
  - Ecker, Beatrice
    - "The Story of the James W. Helme Candidacy for Nomination in the Famous Senatorial Election of 1918", 1943 (Box 2)
  - Edmonds, John
    - "The Rise of the Student-Progressive Movement, First Phase: The Round Table Club 1931) ", 1940 (Box 2)
  - Efty, Muriel
    - "The Kindergarten Movement in Michigan History", 1947 (Box 2)
      (History 290)
  - Eggerling, Magdalen H.
    - "Emma Amelia Ball: Enlightened Pioneer", 1959 (Box 2)
  - Everson, Hillary J.
    - "Fifteenth Michigan Regiment Infantry, 1861-1865" (Box 2)
  - Forshee, Evelyn
    - "Bibliographical Report on The Attitude of Woodbrige N. Ferris Toward the National Prohibition Laws 1922-1928" (Box 2)
  - Foster, Ruth M.
    - "Early Settlements and Travel on the Old Territorial Road", 1945 (Box 2)
      (History 335, 336)
  - Hantula, J.N.
    - "The Michigan School of Religion" (Box 2)
  - Fredsell, Harold F.
    - "Bibliography: The History of the Presbyterian Church in Michigan" (Box 2)
    - "The Need of Publishing a History of the Presbyterian Church in Michigan" (Box 2)
  - Freitag, Alfred J.
    - "The Detroit Gazette and the Emigration to Michigan, 1817-1830", 1947 (Box 2)
    - "The Detroit Young Men's Society: A Brief Historical Survey" 1948) 1939) (Box 2)
  - Gill, Robert L.
    - "The Booker T. Washington Trade Association" (Box 2)
  - Good, R. Allen
    - "Transportation in the Copper Country of Michigan", 1937 (Box 2)
  - Goodrich, Robert E.
    - "Thomas McIntyre Cooley" (Box 2)
      College Honors 393
  - Grain, Murray
    - "The Incorporation of the Township of Livonia", 1958 (Box 2)
  - Grambau, Harry
    - "Michigan County Organization", 1938 (Box 2)
  - Gratz, Delbert L.
    - "Outline for The History of the Mennonites in Michigan", 1945 (Box 2)
  - Green, Grace Helen
    - "A History of the Public Two Year College in Michigan", 1958 (Box 2)
  - Greve, Esther B.
    - "Highlights of the Educational Philosophy of John D. Pierce" (Box 2)
  - Grimes, Wellington V.
    - "A History of the Detroit University School", 1944 (Box 2)
  - Grinke, Barbara V.
    - "Austin Blair, Governor of Michigan 1861-1864", 1959 (Box 2)
    - "The Royal Oak Tribune and The Daily Tribune, 1902-1952", 1958 (Box 2)
  - Groat, Anne L.
    - "A Study of Washtenaw Presbytery, Michigan in Relation to the Historical Developments in the United States, 1837-1870", 1944 (Box 2)
    - "Theodore Foster: An Early Michigan Liberal", 1943 (Box 2)
      (American History 341s)
  - Gustafson, Waino V.
    - "The Secretary of State as Publisher and Distributor of the Laws", 1936 (Box 3)
  - Guter, Lawrence J.
    - "Father Gabriel Richard S.S", 1947 (Box 3)
  - Hagaman, Ardath
    - "Women of the Old Northwest in the Antislavery Movement", 1941 (Box 3)
      (History 431, 432)
  - Hansen, Catherine E.
    - "A Unit of Work in Community Civics Correlated with Michigan History", 1941 (Box 3)
    - "Character Sketches of Men in Muskegon and Michigan History", 1941 (Box 3)
  - Hansen, Thomas E.
    - "The Founding and Organizing of the Michigan School of Religion", 1941 (Box 3)
  - Hardy, Margaret B.
    - "Michigan Politics and the Disposal of the Public Domain, 1837-1841", 1943 (Box 3)
  - Hawley, Elizabeth
    - "The Roles of Laura S. Haviland and Caleb D. Randall in the Establishment of the Michigan State Public School for Dependent Children", 1945 (Box 3)
  - Henderson, Raymond F.
    - "Jackson, Michigan in Civil War Days" (Box 3)
    - "Growth of the First Methodist Church: Jackson, Michigan, 1830-1870" (Box 3)
  - Hindman, Jean E.
    - "Federal Aid and Road Building in Michigan" (Box 3)
      (History g201)
  - Holland, Allen A.
    - "The Negro and the Industrial Workers of the World", 1942 (Box 3)
      (Seminar 336)
  - Holman, Donald A.
    - "The Board of Regents of the University of Michigan During the Administration of President Alexander G. Ruthven, 1929-1949" (Box 3)
  - Horine, Charlotte C.
    - "Bibliographical Report on the Canal Movement in Michigan, 1835-1855" (Box 3)
  - Hoskins, Lewis M.
    - " The Michigan Daily and the World War (I)" (Box 3)
    - "Notes For Paper on The Michigan Daily and the World War" (Box 3)
  - Huang, Ray
    - "The Sit-Down Strike Against the General Motors Corporation in 1937 and Public Opinion" (Box 3)
  - Huber, John Parker
    - "The Western Experience as a Pleasure Experience", 1965 (Box 3)
  - Hull, Jean D.
    - "The Operation of the Michigan State Supreme Court, 1858-1885", 1950 (Box 3)
    - "The Early Years of the University of Michigan with Brief Biographical Sketches of the Trustees", 1949 (Box 3)
  - Hutchins, Richard G.
    - "King Strang in The Michigan Legislature", 1959 (Box 3)
  - Jacobs, Edward S.
    - "History of the Wisconsin-Michigan Boundary Dispute, 1885-1936" (Box 3)
  - John, Arthur
    - "A History of the Labadie Collection of Labor and Radical Literature on the University of Michigan Library" (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Marvin L.
    - "Henry Ford's Primary Campaign" (Box 3)
  - Johnston, Geneva M.
    - "Michigan Pioneer Alexander B. Copley", 1943 (Box 3)
  - Jolly, James A
    - "The Social Philosophy of Frank Murphy" (Box 3)
  - Jones, Alan
    - "The Philosophy of Thomas Cooley", 1951 (Box 3)
      (History)
  - Kedney, Emma E.
    - "The Michigan College of Mining and Technology, 1885-1899" (Box 3)
      (History 201)
  - Kennedy, Myllicent
    - "The 'Soo' and Its First Water Power Companies in the Rapids" (Box 3)
  - Kinsey, Lyle C.
    - "The History of Redford Union School District No. 1", 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - Kortesoja, Arthur H.
    - "Dickinson County Records: An Evaluation", 1947 (Box 3)
  - Krueger, Paul
    - "Legislation in the Development of the County Normal Training Classes" (Box 3)
  - Lampinen, Lily Gay
    - "Liquor, Ladies, and the War of 1912", 1960 (Box 3)
  - Larson, Arvid
    - "The Railroad Aid Decision: Public Reaction in the Case People vs. Salem", 1950 (Box 3)
  - Laub, Laura
    - "Education for Service", 1959 (Box 3)
  - Lehmann, Charles F.